{
  "title": "2.4",
  "definitions": {
    "STAMPEDE": {
      "word": "STAMPEDE",
      "phonetic": "(stam-pEd')",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a wild rush, sudden charge </p><p>A STAMPEDE is a sudden, wild rush, usually of animals that have become frightened and run blindly. In a STAMPEDE the animals are out of control; they are so crazy with fear they will trample anything in their way. </p><p>“The cattle STAMPEDE destroyed the field of new corn.” </p><p>“Don’t shoot your rifle now. The noise will cause a STAMPEDE.” </p><p>STAMPEDE can also be used in a general sense about any wild rush. </p><p>“The announcement of the big sale almost caused a STAMPEDE of shoppers to the store.” </p><p>STAMPEDE is also a verb, which means to rush wildly or overrun. </p><p>“The starving people STAMPEDED the supply wagons.”</p>"
    },
    "PROCLAIM": {
      "word": "PROCLAIM",
      "phonetic": "(prO-klAm')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to declare openly, announce </p><p>To PROCLAIM something is to announce it openly and publicly. </p><p>“After he won the fight the boxer was PROCLAIMED champion of the world.” </p><p>“When his father died the noblemen PROCLAIMED him king.” </p><p>Often PROCLAIM has an official sense to it. </p><p>“The governor PROCLAIMED next Monday a state holiday.” </p><p>A PROCLAMATION is an official announcement. </p><p>“Lincoln issued a PROCLAMATION that ended slavery in America.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: PROCLAMATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "INCIDENT": {
      "word": "INCIDENT",
      "phonetic": "(in'-sÔøΩdent",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an event, occurrence, happening </p><p>An INCIDENT is simply something that happens, an event. Usually an INCIDENT is small or unimportant. </p><p>“It was just one of those unpleasant INCIDENTS that happen every day.” </p><p>Often, though, the word is used about a seemingly minor event which could lead to serious consequences. </p><p>“The arrest of the novelist became a serious international INCIDENT.” </p><p>“There were so many violent INCIDENTS at the border that both countries threatened to declare war.”</p>"
    },
    "MINDFUL": {
      "word": "MINDFUL",
      "phonetic": "(mlnd'-fal)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">aware, careful, attentive </p><p>MINDFUL is made up of two parts: <i class=“def-ital\">mind</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">ful</i>.  If your mind is full of something, you are very aware of it. MINDFUL means “keeping in mind,” aware. </p><p>“He was MINDFUL of the orders he had been given.” </p><p>“You should be MINDFUL of the danger.” </p><p>“You must be MINDFUL that some of these animals could hurt you.” </p><p>Usage: MINDFUL is usually followed by <i class=“def-ital\">of</i>.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ful</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "PREVIOUS": {
      "word": "PREVIOUS",
      "phonetic": "(prE'-vE-as)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">former, earlier, prior </p><p>PREVIOUS means “happening before” something else, former.  </p><p>“All the PREVIOUS reports were wrong. Only the one we are putting out now is correct.” </p><p>“We did well that season, but we did even better in the PREVIOUS season.” </p><p>“After working there for a while he went back to his PREVIOUS job as a salesman.” </p><p>PREVIOUS is often used with <i class=“def-ital\">to</i> to mean <i class=“def-ital\">before</i>. </p><p>“PREVIOUS to the speech there was a wonderful dinner.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">pre-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "QUARANTINE": {
      "word": "QUARANTINE",
      "phonetic": "(kwor'-ÔøΩn-tEn)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to isolate or separate from others; to prevent the spread of a disease </p><p>QUARANTINE is both a verb and a noun. To QUARANTINE a person is to keep him apart from others while he has a disease, or while he is suspected of having a disease, to make sure that the disease doesn’t spread. QUARANTINE comes from the Latin word for forty, because originally a person had to be kept isolated for a period of forty days. </p><p>“You can take your dog to England, but it will have to be kept in QUARANTINE for six months.” </p><p>“The entire ship was QUARANTINED when one of the passengers came down with smallpox.”</p>"
    },
    "RECREATION": {
      "word": "RECREATION",
      "phonetic": "(rek-rE-A'-shan)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">play, amusement </p><p>RECREATION is something that refreshes you by providing you with amusement or entertainment. </p><p>“Walking is a pleasant RECREATION.” </p><p>“His favorite RECREATION is watching television.” </p><p>“She works too hard. She hardly has any time for RECREATION.” </p><p>The adjective from RECREATION is RECREATIONAL. RECREATIONAL activities are things like games, sports, or hobbies which provide RECREATION. </p><p>Other forms of the word: RECREATIONAL, adj.</p>"
    },
    "SEGMENT": {
      "word": "SEGMENT",
      "phonetic": "(seg'-mant)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a part, section, division </p><p>A SEGMENT is a section, a piece of a larger whole. </p><p>“One SEGMENT of the magazine is made up of business reports.” </p><p>“Mr. Sweeney is the counselor for a large SEGMENT of the junior class.” </p><p>“Mrs. Ames gave each of the children a SEGMENT of the orange.”</p>"
    },
    "SUBMERGE": {
      "word": "SUBMERGE",
      "phonetic": "(sab-merj')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to place underwater; to go under water, sink </p><p> To SUBMERGE something is to plunge it into water. </p><p>“The blacksmith quickly SUBMERGED the glowing horseshoe in a bucket of water.” </p><p>When something SUBMERGES, it goes underwater. </p><p>“The submarine SUBMERGED and quickly disappeared from sight.” </p><p>“The treasure lay SUBMERGED in ten feet of water.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">sub-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "TURQUOISE": {
      "word": "TURQUOISE",
      "phonetic": "(ter'-kwoyz",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">blue-green </p><p>TURQUOISE, when used as a noun, is a stone that is often blue-green in color. TURQUOISE, as an adjective, is used about anything with this blue-green color. </p><p>“Her eyes are almost TURQUOISE in color.” </p><p>“My TURQUOISE dress is the color of sea at mid-day.”</p>"
    },
    "UTMOST": {
      "word": "UTMOST",
      "phonetic": "(uht'-mOst)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">greatest, most extreme </p><p>UTMOST means “of the highest degree possible\"—that is, the furthest, the most, the greatest, and so on. </p><p>“This job requires the UTMOST skill and intelligence.” </p><p>“This meeting will take place in the UTMOST secrecy.” </p><p>UTMOST is also a noun, meaning “the most that is possible or that one can do.” </p><p>“He enjoyed life to the UTMOST\"—that is, to the greatest degree possible. </p><p>“This hotel will give you the UTMOST in comfort and service.” </p><p>“We will do our UTMOST to finish the job on Saturday.”</p>"
    },
    "VICTOR": {
      "word": "VICTOR",
      "phonetic": "(vik'-tar)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a winner, conqueror </p><p>A VICTOR is a person who defeats another in battle or any other kind of contest. </p><p>“This year the VICTOR in the weight-lifting contest was a Russian.” </p><p>“Harry Smith will be our mayor next year because he was the VICTOR in last week’s election.” </p><p>A VICTOR wins a VICTORY; he is VICTORIOUS. </p><p>“After his famous VICTORY, the VICTORIOUS general received all the glory due a VICTOR.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: VICTORY, n. VICTORIOUS, adj.</p>"
    },
    "DWELL": {
      "word": "DWELL",
      "phonetic": "(dwel)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to live, reside; to speak, write, or think at length </p><p>To DWELL in or at a place is to make your home there. </p><p>“She DWELT all her life in the house where she was born.” </p><p>“Many interesting people DWELL in that section of town.” </p><p>In another sense, to DWELL on or upon something is to speak, write, or think about it at length. </p><p>“I hate to DWELL on this, but you still owe me five dollars.” </p><p>“In the first few chapters the author DWELLS on the problems of the early settlers.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DWELLING, n. </p><p>Usage: The past tense of DWELL is DWELT or DWELLED.</p>"
    },
    "QUESTIONABLE": {
      "word": "QUESTIONABLE",
      "phonetic": "(kwes'-chÔøΩn-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">doubtful, uncertain </p><p> Something which is QUESTIONABLE is able to be QUESTIONED, is open to QUESTION. </p><p>“The referee made a QUESTIONABLE call\"—that is, we are not certain that it was wrong, but we don’t think it was right. </p><p>“It was QUESTIONABLE whether or not we would make it to school on time.” </p><p>“He thought our results were QUESTIONABLE, so we checked them and discovered we had made a mistake.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Certain</i> is the most commonly chosen incorrect answer on the Pretest. It is the exact opposite of QUESTIONABLE. Perhaps people who choose <i class=“def-ital\">certain</i> are confusing QUESTIONABLE with <i class=“def-ital\">unquestionable</i>, which means “not open to QUESTION,” <i class=“def-ital\">certain</i>. </p><p>Other forms of the word: QUESTION, n., v.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-able</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "ROUSE": {
      "word": "ROUSE",
      "phonetic": "(rowz)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to awaken, stir, excite </p><p>To ROUSE someone is to stir or awaken him. </p><p>“The fire alarm ROUSED them from their sleep.” </p><p>You can ROUSE someone <i class=“def-ital\">to</i> something as well as <i class=“def-ital\">from</i> something. </p><p>“The speaker’s words ROUSED the crowd to action.” </p><p>“I was ROUSED to anger by his insults.” </p><p>ROUSE is often used with <i class=“def-ital\">up</i>. </p><p>“They ROUSED up their friends and made them help too.” </p><p>ROUSING is an adjective which means <i class=“def-ital\">exciting</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">stirring</i>. </p><p>“We gave a ROUSING cheer when the team came on the field.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ROUSING, adj.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "4",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Join the STAMPEDE.",
          "answers": [
            "meeting",
            "crowd",
            "wild rush",
            "defense line",
            "cattle"
          ],
          "word": "STAMPEDE",
          "correct": "wild rush"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To PROCLAIM it.",
          "answers": [
            "invent",
            "declare",
            "want",
            "oppose",
            "celebrate"
          ],
          "word": "PROCLAIM",
          "correct": "declare"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unusual INCIDENT.",
          "answers": [
            "crime",
            "problem",
            "idea",
            "complaint",
            "event"
          ],
          "word": "INCIDENT",
          "correct": "event"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MINDFUL of his duties.",
          "answers": [
            "aware",
            "fond",
            "afraid",
            "forgetful",
            "ashamed"
          ],
          "word": "MINDFUL",
          "correct": "aware"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PREVIOUS job.",
          "answers": [
            "former",
            "steady",
            "second",
            "important",
            "new"
          ],
          "word": "PREVIOUS",
          "correct": "former"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To QUARANTINE them.",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "divide",
            "isolate",
            "protect",
            "free"
          ],
          "word": "QUARANTINE",
          "correct": "isolate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "More time for RECREATION.",
          "answers": [
            "sleep",
            "play",
            "work",
            "practice",
            "thinking"
          ],
          "word": "RECREATION",
          "correct": "play"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This SEGMENT.",
          "answers": [
            "word",
            "choice",
            "part",
            "idea",
            "time"
          ],
          "word": "SEGMENT",
          "correct": "part"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Completely SUBMERGED.",
          "answers": [
            "open",
            "lost",
            "sunk",
            "wet",
            "joined"
          ],
          "word": "SUBMERGE",
          "correct": "sunk"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TURQUOISE dresses.",
          "answers": [
            "blue-green",
            "foreign",
            "dark-red",
            "white",
            "gold"
          ],
          "word": "TURQUOISE",
          "correct": "blue-green"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The UTMOST danger.",
          "answers": [
            "unknown",
            "least",
            "next",
            "famous",
            "greatest"
          ],
          "word": "UTMOST",
          "correct": "greatest"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Who was the VICTOR?",
          "answers": [
            "loser",
            "minister",
            "general",
            "winner",
            "leader"
          ],
          "word": "VICTOR",
          "correct": "winner"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Where does she DWELL?",
          "answers": [
            "live",
            "eat",
            "study",
            "travel",
            "work"
          ],
          "word": "DWELL",
          "correct": "live"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was QUESTIONABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "difficult",
            "impossible",
            "doubtful",
            "certain",
            "unnecessary"
          ],
          "word": "QUESTIONABLE",
          "correct": "doubtful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ROUSE the people.",
          "answers": [
            "cheat",
            "awaken",
            "trap",
            "unite",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "ROUSE",
          "correct": "awaken"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is it dangerous to he in the middle of a STAMPEDE?",
          "word": "STAMPEDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually PROCLAIM secrets?",
          "word": "PROCLAIM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is going to the dentist an INCIDENT in people's lives?",
          "word": "INCIDENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should a driver be MINDFUL of dangers on the road?",
          "word": "MINDFUL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Did the Civil War happen PREVIOUS to the War of Independence?",
          "word": "PREVIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are people who aren't sick ever QUARANTINED?",
          "word": "QUARANTINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is swimming a form of RECREATION?",
          "word": "RECREATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a chapter a SEGMENT of a book?",
          "word": "SEGMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a rock be SUBMERGED?",
          "word": "SUBMERGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can the sky ever appear TURQUOISE?",
          "word": "TURQUOISE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are people who are doing their UTMOST really trying?",
          "word": "UTMOST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the VICTOR in a race the one who finishes last?",
          "word": "VICTOR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you DWELL somewhere?",
          "word": "DWELL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a close call by an umpire in baseball be QUESTIONABLE?",
          "word": "QUESTIONABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a sleeping person usually be ROUSED by a leaf falling?",
          "word": "ROUSE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The STAMPEDE was quiet all night, but acted up again in the morning.",
          "word": "STAMPEDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Sam said he caught the criminal, so he PROCLAIMED the reward.",
          "word": "PROCLAIM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This book is about several INCIDENTS that took place in the town of Salem.",
          "word": "INCIDENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I won't he MINDFUL if you want to come with me.",
          "word": "MINDFUL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She had no PREVIOUS experience, hut still she did the job very well.",
          "word": "PREVIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The horse was kept in QUARANTINE until it was completely cured.",
          "word": "QUARANTINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Scientists think it has been five billion years since the RECREATION of the earth.",
          "word": "RECREATION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "One SEGMENT of the movie takes place in Spain.",
          "word": "SEGMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SUBMERGED from the water and walked up onto the beach.",
          "word": "SUBMERGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Barry turned TURQUOISE with anger at the insult.",
          "word": "TURQUOISE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Dave enjoyed himself to the UTMOST during his vacation.",
          "word": "UTMOST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were VICTORIOUS in their battle with the enemy forces.",
          "word": "VICTOR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His speech will DWELL on the problems of getting a job.",
          "word": "DWELL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His honesty is QUESTIONABLE. There are rumors that he takes bribes.",
          "word": "QUESTIONABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The coach's speech ROUSED the team to try even harder.",
          "word": "ROUSE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "STAMPEDE",
          "answers": [
            "speed",
            "joy",
            "fear"
          ],
          "word": "STAMPEDE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROCLAIM",
          "answers": [
            "shout",
            "whisper",
            "state"
          ],
          "word": "PROCLAIM",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INCIDENT",
          "answers": [
            "happening",
            "hope",
            "occurrence"
          ],
          "word": "INCIDENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MINDFUL",
          "answers": [
            "aware",
            "careful",
            "brilliant"
          ],
          "word": "MINDFUL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PREVIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "easier",
            "past",
            "earlier"
          ],
          "word": "PREVIOUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "QUARANTINE",
          "answers": [
            "separate",
            "isolate",
            "tax"
          ],
          "word": "QUARANTINE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECREATION",
          "answers": [
            "lessons",
            "games",
            "sports"
          ],
          "word": "RECREATION",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SEGMENT",
          "answers": [
            "most",
            "all",
            "half"
          ],
          "word": "SEGMENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUBMERGE",
          "answers": [
            "sink",
            "dive",
            "sail"
          ],
          "word": "SUBMERGE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TURQUOISE",
          "answers": [
            "green",
            "blue",
            "yellow"
          ],
          "word": "TURQUOISE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UTMOST",
          "answers": [
            "extra",
            "furthest",
            "best"
          ],
          "word": "UTMOST",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VICTOR",
          "answers": [
            "conqueror",
            "fighter",
            "winner"
          ],
          "word": "VICTOR",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DWELL",
          "answers": [
            "stay",
            "live",
            "visit"
          ],
          "word": "DWELL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "QUESTIONABLE",
          "answers": [
            "doubtful",
            "untrue",
            "uncertain"
          ],
          "word": "QUESTIONABLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ROUSE",
          "answers": [
            "excite",
            "worry",
            "stir"
          ],
          "word": "ROUSE",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}